So in order to build this error function,
所以 为了构建这个误差函数
let's recall something we saw before, the perceptron algorithm.
我们来回顾一下之前出现过的 感知机算法
The perceptron algorithm works in the following way.
感知机算法通过以下方式工作
You have some data points like this,
我们有一些红色和蓝色的数据点
blue and red, and we want to find a perfect line that splits them.
需要一条完美的线来划分这些点
Now, perfect line has equation Wx + b = 0,
现在 这条线的方程式为 Wx+b=0
where W and x are vectors and b is a scalar.
其中 W 和 x 为向量 b 为标量
So it looks more like this,
所以它更像是
w1x1 + w2x2 + b = 0.
w1x1+w2x2+b=0
As a quick example, let's say the equation is 3x1 + 4x2 + 5 = 0.
简单示例一下 假设方程式为 3x1+4x2+5=0
So we want to punish this line with some error function,
然后我们希望 用误差函数来惩罚这条线
and the error function roughly measures how many points are misclassified.
粗略地测算出有多少点被误分类
It actually measures something closer to the sum of
它实际上更像是在测算所有误分类的点
the distances of these misclassified points to the boundary.
到这条线的距离的总和
So we can split this into two sets,
我们可以将这些点分成红点和蓝点
the red points and the blue points,
两个数据集
and our error function is going to punish those two red points on the left that are on
我们的误差函数会根据这些点到主线的距离
top of the line and those two blue points on the right that are below the line,
惩罚左边线上方的两个红点
but it's going to punish them according to their distance to the main line.
及右边线下方的两个蓝点
So half of our error function will look like this.
所以 我们误差函数的一半就是这样的
It's going to be the blue area that is over the line.
即线条上方的蓝色区域
So the more a red point is into the blue area,
红点距离蓝色区域越近
the more it gets punished.
就会受到越多惩罚
This means that the point that is close to the line gets punished a little bit,
这意味着距离线近的点惩罚小
and the point that is far from the line gets punished more.
距离线远的惩罚大
And the other part of the error does the complete opposite.
该误差函数的另一部分则完全相反
It punishes the blue points that are in the red area.
它惩罚红色区域的蓝点
The points that are close to the line don't get punished much,
距离线近的点惩罚较小
and the ones that are far from the line get punished a lot more.
距离线远的点惩罚较大
But let's actually put some math here.
我们在这里应用一下数学
Let's ask how much is the error at every point.
思考每个点的误差是多少
So we have that our equation as we said is Wx + b = 0,
我们之前提到有方程式 Wx+b=0
which is a linear equation.
这是一个线性方程
Now, Wx + b takes all the values, so in particular,
Wx+b 可以是任意值
it is one of the line that is parallel to the main line and a little bit
它是一条和主线平行
above and then it takes the value 2, 3, 4 successively.
且略高于主线的线 依次取值 2 3 4
And the same thing on the negative side,
同样 在另一方
it takes the values minus 1,
取值 -1
minus 2, minus 3,
-2 -3
minus 4 et cetera.
-4 等等
And, basically, this is going to be the error.
基本上 这就是误差
It's going to be the value of Wx + b.
它就是 Wx+b 的值
Actually, since we have negative numbers,
实际上 因为我们有负数
it's going to be the absolute value of Wx + b.
它取的是 Wx+b 的绝对值
So now, let's calculate the errors for the misclassified points.
现在 我们来计算被误分类的点的误差
This point, for example, gets an error of 2.5,
比如 这个红点误差为 2.5
since the red point lies in 2.5 line,
因为它落在线 2.5 上
where Wx + b is 2.5.
在这条线上 Wx+b 为 2.5
This one has an error of 0.5.
这个误差为 0.5
And these points over here have errors of one and two since
这些点的误差为 1 和 2
let's remember the error is the absolute value of Wx + b.
不要忘了这边误差为 Wx+b 的绝对值
And then to calculate the whole error that this model gives us, we just add them.
然后 我们把这个模型给出的所有误差相加 计算出来
So this model gives us an error of six.
所以这个模型给出的误差为 6
So now we put these two together,
现在我们将这两部分合起来
and we conclude that this model has an error of six.
我们得到结论 这个模型的误差为 6
And the idea will be to minimize this error using gradient descent in
然后 通过梯度下降法来最小化误差
order to find the ideal W and b that give us the best possible cut.
从而找到理想的 W 和 b 来给出可能的最优分割
And that is the perceptron algorithm.
就是感知机算法